## **Olaoluwa Samuel**

I am a proactive, innovative engineer and leader with 3 years of development experience. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. I am a proficient JavaScript developer. Softwares I have built include; a standard blog app, Chuck-Norris joke app, banking app, and many more.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Decagon, Nigeria — JavaScript Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2021 - Date

- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.
- Implemented a Transfer service API with TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, Docker, MongoDB
- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, Postgres, or NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.
- Built several endpoints using graphql and rest API.
- Built API endpoints for an electronic voting app using Node js utilizing jwt for authentication.
- Built the get all jobs and get all applications endpoints for an IT app called apogga using Node js, typescript, express and ran tests using supertest and jest
- Implemented a transfer service app using Node, typescript, express, MongoDB, and docker
- Exposure to scrum and agile methodologies
- Incorporated the MongoDB transactions API to ensure that some database operations either succeed or fail.

# **InksNation International,** Lagos, Nigeria — Javascript *Software Engineer*

APRIL 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- A member of a team that developed a world-class crypto-currency solution.
- Built reliable frontend page with HTML, CSS, and vanilla javascript.
- Transformed the already existing website to react app.
- Managed state and HTTP requests with Axios and Redux.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.
- Exposure to agile methodologies.

4, Mariam Abiodun avenue off babatayo oni

way, Mosan,

Lagos State, Nigeria, NG. +2348189389584, 7062698820

Email: olaoluofficial@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/olaoluwa-

samuel-01845711b

Github:https://github.com/OlaoluOfficial/

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- HTML 5
- CSS
- Tailwind
- Bootstrap
- Javascript
- Nodejs
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Express Framework
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Postgresql
- SQL
- Heroku
- Netlify
- Supertest
- Morcha
- Multer
- Firebase
- Docker
- Jira
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven Development
- Agile methodologies

### **PROJECTS**

#### **BLOG APP:**

A complex blog app that allows users to create, edit and delete accounts and posts.

Technologies Used - React.js, Node, Multer, CSS, etc.

Link: https://github.com/OlaoluOfficial/blog-react-app

#### **Chuck-Norris Jokes:**

An application where users go to in order to laugh and ease off. The app fetches the famous Chuck Norris jokes and displays endless to the users.

Technologies Used - React and Chuck-Norris API.

Link: https://og-chuck-norris.netlify.app/

### **Banking App:**

An API application works like a real-life banking services app where users are able to create bank accounts, send money, receive money, view balances, and many more.

Technologies Used: Nodejs, Express, Jest, Docker, MongoDB,

Mongoose, Heroku.

Link: https://og-transfer-express.herokuapp.com/balance

#### Star Wars API:

This cool single-page application interacts with the star-wars API and interacts with the frontend from just the javascript file, which means the whole logic behind the page was just done from the js file.

Technologies Used - Vanillajs.

Link: http://og-star-wars-api.netlify.app/

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bowen University** — B.Sc

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JUNE 2016

Second Class Upper - Bachelor of Science degree in Finance From Bowen University, Osun, Nigeria